Sani Muhammad Jamil

Fullstack Software Developer

Abuja, Nigeria

+234 7035483237

portfolio.jamsanz.xyz

github.com/jamsanz

Summary

Experienced Full-stack Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Skilled in Front-end and Back-End Web Development and Cross-platform mobile development. Strong software engineering professional with a Bachelor's degree focused on Computer Science.

Skills

HTML, CSS3, Javascript ES6, Typescript, Reactjs + Redux, Nextjs, Nodejs, Expressjs, Ejs, Firebase, PHP, MongoDB, Mongoose, MySQL, Bootstrap, Reactstrap, Material UI, Tailwind CSS, Flutter, React Native, Java, Python, Git.

Work experience

Fullstack software developer

2021-04 - Till date

Wootlab Innovations

- Part of the team that developed software applications used by an organization (UNDP), targeted at
 achieving the organization's business objectives. These applications
 handled over 700,000 records for a national program. NJFP
- Responsible for working on a range of projects with React & Nextjs as the primary frontend technologies.
- Designing and developing appealing interactive websites on a daily basis.
- Collaborating with UI/UX designers and backend developers in delivering user stories into real software solutions.
- Working with robust REST API(s) for large enterprise applications
- Worked with Google places and autocomplete API(s) on a taxi Application (Uber Clone) React Native
- Integrated Google Search API on a search application (Google Search Clone) React
- Built a number of restful API(s) with Express and Typescript
- Assisted in training 52 Nigerian youths on web development(HTML, CSS, Javascript & Nodejs) and android development -Basecamp (Bootcamp)
- Trained a number of kids on game development (scratch programming) KidsCypher

IT Intern 09-2018 - 12-2018

Fixable Systems

Setting up small offices (Switching & routing) - Networking

Computer software(OS) and hardware repairs - Maintenance

Managing databases - Database Administrator (MYSQL)

IT intern 2017-09 - 2017-12

Khemsafe computer institute

Graphics designer:
 Design and visualization of company logos.

Design and visualization of flyers and banners.

• Web developer.

Design and development of basic websites using HTML & CSS

Projects

- Nigerian Jubilee Fellowship Programme (NJFP) https://njfp.ng Sub-components:
 - E-leaning
 - Monitoring & evaluation system
 - Applicants portal
 - Alumni platform

Technologies: React, Redux, Next, Typescript, Java (Springboot), MySQL

Role: Frontend team member.

• Oil Palm Growers Association of Nigerian (OPGAN) - https://opgan.ng

Technologies: React, Next, Typescript, Material UI, Nodejs (Express), MongoDB (Mongoose)

Role: Sole developer

• Uber Clone (Mobile App iOS & Android) - https://expo.dev/@jamsanz/uber-clone

Technologies: React Native, Redux, Google Places API, Google Autocomplete API

Role: Sole developer

• Google Search clone - https://google.jamsanz.xyz

Technologies: React, Google Search API

Role: Sole developer

• Amazon Clone - https://amazon.jamsanz.xyz

Technologies: React, Next, Next Auth, Redux, Firebase

Role: Sole developer

• Mediaplus Consultancy - https://atmediaplus-consulatncy.org

Technologies: React, Next, Typescript, Node (Express), MongoDB (Mongoose)

Role: Sole developer

Education

Bachelor's Degree

2016-01 - 2020-07

Al-Qalam University

BSc. Computer Science Second class upper

4.4

Certifications

- Javascript Certificate
- React + Redux Certificate
- CSS Certificate
- jQuery Certificate
- MySQL Certificate
- PHP Certificate
- HTML Certificate
- Certificate in making businesses digital and global

References

Available on request.